<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Shane Peelar's Blog</title><link>https://inbetweennames.net/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Shane Peelar's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 Shane Peelar</copyright><atom:link href="https://inbetweennames.net/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2.5D Software Renderer Demo (COMP-3520 Computer Graphics Lab Materials)</title><link>https://inbetweennames.net/projects/2021-05-05-comp3520/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://inbetweennames.net/projects/2021-05-05-comp3520/</guid><description>When I was teaching the labs for COMP-3520 with Dr. Robert Kent, I put together a little demo to help explain certain concepts during the labs. It is a 2.5D software rendered engine. That is, there&amp;rsquo;s no OpenGL or Direct3D or Vulkan or anything like that involved: this renders directly to an array, treating it as though it were a linear framebuffer (2D array of pixels). Each lab, I would demonstrate a new concept using some addition to the demo.</description></item><item><title>Interstate '76/Nitro pack netcode patches</title><link>https://inbetweennames.net/projects/interstate76anet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://inbetweennames.net/projects/interstate76anet/</guid><description>This page was brought over from my old cs.uwindsor.ca/~peelar home page. The information presented here is still accurate, however, if you want to try these patches, I encourage you to download one of the patch bundles from interstate76.com instead of dragging and dropping the files here into your installation, as you will get a few other goodies as well that way.
Introduction These Interstate 76/Nitro Pack game modifications allow you to once again play games over the internet with other people, without requiring your machine to be directly connected to the net.</description></item></channel></rss>