<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>i76 on Shane Peelar's Blog</title><link>https://inbetweennames.net/tags/i76/</link><description>Recent content in i76 on Shane Peelar's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 Shane Peelar</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://inbetweennames.net/tags/i76/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fast reciprocal square root... in 1997?!</title><link>https://inbetweennames.net/blog/2021-05-06-i76rsqrt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://inbetweennames.net/blog/2021-05-06-i76rsqrt/</guid><description>This article is part of my series on reverse engineering Interstate &amp;lsquo;76, with my current goal being to add a Vulkan renderer to the game. I&amp;rsquo;m basing this work directly on UCyborg&amp;rsquo;s patches which include many much-needed fixups to the game, including my own patches for the netcode.
Introduction Everyone is familiar with the famous fast reciprocal square root function in the Quake 3 source code. And, as noted on Wikipedia, solutions have existed for computing the fast reciprocal square root for many years before that, with perhaps the earliest implementation in 1986.</description></item><item><title>Interstate '76 Reverse Engineering</title><link>https://inbetweennames.net/blog/2021-05-04-interstate-76-reverse-engineering-efforts-the-story-so-far/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://inbetweennames.net/blog/2021-05-04-interstate-76-reverse-engineering-efforts-the-story-so-far/</guid><description>I played a lot of videogames when I was growing up &amp;ndash; one of them, I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself coming back to time and time again:
The game is called Interstate &amp;lsquo;76. Set in an alternate-history version if 1976 where vigilantes and &amp;ldquo;creepers&amp;rdquo; duke it out in souped up muscle cars with guns, rockets, and all kinds of other gadgets. On game consoles, the closest analogue would have been the Twisted Metal series, but Interstate was far less dark and had somewhat deep simulation mechanics involved: you could customize your car quite thoroughly and these customizations had big effects on how you&amp;rsquo;d drive it.</description></item><item><title>Interstate '76/Nitro pack netcode patches</title><link>https://inbetweennames.net/projects/interstate76anet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://inbetweennames.net/projects/interstate76anet/</guid><description>This page was brought over from my old cs.uwindsor.ca/~peelar home page. The information presented here is still accurate, however, if you want to try these patches, I encourage you to download one of the patch bundles from interstate76.com instead of dragging and dropping the files here into your installation, as you will get a few other goodies as well that way.
Introduction These Interstate 76/Nitro Pack game modifications allow you to once again play games over the internet with other people, without requiring your machine to be directly connected to the net.</description></item></channel></rss>